Here's where we are in the lesson map.
このレッスンの図で確認しましょう
Next up, we have to linearize our function h(x).
次に必要なのは線形化で対象は 関数 x の小文字 h です
Remember that this starts with derivatives.
微分係数から始まることを 覚えておいてください
Let's get to it.
では始めましょう
If we generalize our previous example to a higher dimension,
前の例を より高い次元に一般化する場合
the derivative of h(x), with respect to x, is called the Jacobian.
h(x) の x に対する 微分係数はヤコビと呼ばれます
And it's going to be a matrix containing all the partial derivatives.
そしてすべての偏微分係数を含む 行列となります
For example, for my function lower case h,
たとえば 関数の小文字 h では
in the first row over here, I have the first dimension of the function
この最初の行で 関数の第 1 の次元
h1 derived with respect to the first dimension of x,
h1 が導出され x の第 1 の次元
second dimension of x, to the nth dimension of x.
x の第 2 の次元 x の第 n の次元に対応します
And then I repeat this for every dimension of lower case h,
次にこれを小文字 h の 各次元について繰り返します
to be more specific,I know that the measurement function describes
詳しく言うと 測定関数は
three components: range, bearing, and range rate, and
3 要素 つまり距離 方位 範囲レートを記述し
my state is a vector with four components: Px, Py, Vx, Vy.
状態は 4 要素を持つベクターで それぞれ Px Py Vx Vy となります
In that case, the Jacobian matrix Hj is going to be matrix with three rows and
その場合 ヤコビ行列 Hj は 3 行
four columns.
4 列になります
After computing all of these partial derivatives, I obtain this matrix.
これらすべての偏微分係数の計算後に この行列を取得します
If you're interested to see more details about how I got this results,
この結果を得る方法について 関心がある場合は
have a look at the details below.
下の詳細をご覧ください
So let's program this.
これをプログラミングしましょう
Now, I would like you to implement CalculateJacobian function,
では CalculateJacobian 関数を 実装してみてください
which takes our current predicted state and
この関数は現在の 予測状態を使用して
computes the new Jacobian matrix, Hj, that you just saw.
前に説明した新しいヤコビ行列 Hj を計算します
So, for example, if our predicted state is x is equal to 1, 2, 0.2, and 0.4,
たとえば 予測状態が x で 1 2 0.2 0.4 に等しい場合
I would like to output a 3x4 matrix with the following values.
出力する 3x4 の行列は 次の値を持つものとします
Fill in your code here in a CalculateJacobian function.
コードをこの場所の CalculateJacobian 関数に入力してください
Also, you have to make sure you don't divide by 0 when computing the Jacobian.
また ヤコビ計算時には 0 で割らないようにする必要があります
In other words, you have to check that neither x nor y is 0.
つまり x と y のいずれも 0 でないことを確認する必要があります
If this happens, just print out the error message as so.
0 で割ると エラーメッセージがそのように出力されます